Hello everyone, it's me Libre speaking from Berkeh Sheikh Radwan in the north of Ghazza.
And we're in a place, a basin, that used to collect rainwater before the Harb,
before the latest genocide here in Ghazza.
And this used to be a place that collected rainwater.
And then at the desalination plant, it was able to desalinate the water
and we could distribute it to the community.
Clean, fresh water is a huge need and there's a growing need for it.
But throughout the genocide, it's become weaponized.
There have been intentional attacks on desalination plants,
as well as water trucks and aid workers that are distributing water here in Ghazza.
And this is one example of the intentional attacks on infrastructure
that make it more difficult for Palestinians to get access to much-needed drinking water and clean water.
You can see behind me the water building up and it's dirty water
that's filled with bacteria and other things that are really bad for the health.
And people are getting sick because they're forcibly displaced and have to live around it.
And there's no sanitation infrastructure and no access to clean water.
Whereas before, this used to be a place that used to help to distribute water.
Because the desalination plant is cut off and there's a few reasons that we have to consider for that.
One, the Zionist occupation forces intentionally are blocking fuel from getting in.
And if it does get in, it's even harder to get it to the north where we are.
The intentional attack on water infrastructure, workers, desalination plants, water trucks.
And the intentionality behind attacking this infrastructure is to push people, to push Ghazans further south
so that it will be easier for the Zionist military forces not only to occupy Gaza City
but to push and force Ghazans outside of Ghazza.
I'm going to show you a closer look at this and then give you a little bit more of context.
Next, you can see this is the buildup of the dirty water.
And unfortunately, due to the genocidal reality, people are forced to live next to this.
Right?
And with all this bacteria and whatnot.
And also, aid drops.
The aid drops will sometimes fall into this cesspool of dirty water.
And because of desperation, people will go in, swim in this water that has who knows what in it
and come out sick but with a little bit of aid, humanitarian, so-called humanitarian aid,
so that they can take home to their families.
So this is just part of the reality that we're living here in Ghazza that should be amplified.